JESWIN VARKEY GEORGE

Data Analyst, <u>Tableau Desktop Specialist</u> Pune, Maharashtra, India | +91 8129737357 | <u>jeswinygeorge22@gmail.com</u>

Objective

Data professional with 3+ years of experience in the analytics and retail services industry. Excels at data wrangling, data mining and making dashboards using Python, R and Tableau. Seeking to apply my abilities to fill the Data Analyst and machine learning engineer role in your company.

Technologies

LANGUAGES: Python **DATABASES:** PostgreSQL

TOOLS: Tableau, R, MS Excel, Power BI, AzureML

Professional Experience

Infosys (Analytics unit), Pune, Senior Associate Analyst

Feb 2018 - Present

- Project: Data Expert for a retail giant's Global Business Solution Team
 Project duration: January 2020 Present
 Responsibilities:
 - Responsible for data governance and on-boarding of new retailers from the market, solution definition of key initiatives for achieving consumption ready data for critical BI applications.
 - Deliver efficient data analysis and ref data management to the market as per SLA. Track and resolve the data quality issues in the E2E lifecycle.
 - Engage with relevant stockholders of the allocated market to understand their business requirements.
 - Collaborate with the design, development, analytics and UI team to provide the best support and products to the clients.
 - Worked closely with the data and analytics team to resolve and improve the data quality and anomaly detection issues.
 - Creating pipelines for the migration from Cloudera to Azure environment.
 - Automating the different cases of data sanity check using Python.
- **Project:** Creating a baseline demand forecasting model for a Retail giant.

Project duration: September 2019 – December 2019

Team strength: 3 **Responsibilities:**

- Assigned as data wrangler of the team.
- Scrapped websites to extract required data using Python (Beautiful soup).
- Cleaning and organising the unstructured data to tidy format using Python (Pandas).

- Applied EDA to get insights about the data using Python and Tableau.
- Created dashboards using Tableau for presentation to the client and higher management.
- Created forecasting models.
- Project: PLM Data Migration for a retail client
 Project duration: July 2018 August 2019
 Team strength: 55 (Overall 5 teams)

Responsibilities:

- Teams: Data mining, Data matching, Data remediation, UI/BI and testing teams
- Part of the Data matching engine creation team.
- Flagging the inconsistencies among the data from different ERPs using R, MS Excel and PostgreSQL.
- Unit testing and system testing of the developed matching engine.
- Ensure quick response to the issues raised by other teams or final application user.
- Analysing the impact of change request and logged defects at process level and project level.
- Created reports and dashboards using excel and R-shiny to present the results to the stakeholders.
- Mentoring new members joining the team and guiding them to get accustomed to the project environment.
- Achieved matching accuracy of 99.81%.

Udacity, Classroom Mentor

Dec 2017-Feb 2018

- Mentored students pursuing Udacity's Data Analyst Nanodegree program.
- Encouraged and guided 20 students assigned to me.

Education

Coursera, Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau	Sept 2018 - Nov 2018
Udacity, Data Analyst Nanodegree	June 2017 - Dec 2017
SRM University, MTech Communication Systems	July 2015 - May 2017
University of Calicut, BTech ECE	June 2010 - May 2014

Find me online

<u>LinkedIn profile</u> | <u>GitHub profile</u> | <u>Tableau public profile</u> | <u>My Website</u>